Guide to the Yale Cabaret Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Cabaret records
1975-2008
RU 1075
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2
(3 boxes)
The materials consist of photographs, press material, posters, meeting minutes, programs and other materials documenting the management, activities, and productions of the Yale Cabaret.
Yale Cabaret
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 22-E (YRG 22-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and projects of the Yale School of Drama.).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Yale Cabaret, 2008
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Cabaret was established in 1968 in the old Phi Gamma Alpha fraternity house (217 Park St) as a coffee shop with the purpose of doing "experimental work" and providing a space for guest artists, faculty, and students to perform. On November 8, 1968, the Cabaret opened is doors with its first performance by Alvin Epstein and Martha Schlamme, singing the songs of Kurt Weill.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs, press material, posters, meeting minutes, programs and other materials documenting the management, activities, and productions of the Yale Cabaret.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Music-halls (Variety-theaters, cabarets, etc.); Theater management; Theater; Photographs; Yale Cabaret; Yale School of Drama; Yale University -- Administration
- Yale Cabaret records, 1975-2008; Accession 2009-A-108
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2044.
  - Misc. B/W Photos (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B/W Famous Actor Photos, Circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Undated Photos, Circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Arthur Pepine's Files, 1975-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Menus, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Board Meetings, 1990-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Sponsorship, 1997-2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Posters/Programs, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
  - Photos, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Production Handbook, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Opening/Season Press, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photos, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Seasons/Menus, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cabaret, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Romeo and Juliet, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Dancing on the Edge of the World, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Fever, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Planes, Trains, and Puppeteering Politics, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Buffalo Soldier, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Wash Your Mouth Out, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Tango Palace, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Y2K XMAS, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The Women, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Malady of Death, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Polariod Stories, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Le Grand Guignol, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Hot Lunch Jam, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The Love of Don Perlimplin and Belisa in the Garden, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Whirligig, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Rain Delay, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Two by Tennessee, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Sherlock Holmes and The Adventures of Making Whoopee, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - =celebration, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Press and Reviews, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Board/Press/Presentations, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Production Handbook, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - All School Meeting and Season, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Marketing/Survey, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Mission/Calendar/Misc, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Press and Reviews, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Board Mtg/Budget Info, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Meeting Notes, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Senior Staff Meetings, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Advisory Board Meetings, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Communiques, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Spring Season, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - 35th Anniversary, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Other Admin, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Budget, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Misc. Production Photos, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 54-55)
  - Ubu is King, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Zombie Attack, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - A Bang, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Sueno, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Pins and Needles Project, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Santaland Diaries, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Production Handbook, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Two Rooms, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Philoctetes, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Spooky 24 Hour Theater, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Tape, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Unwrap Your Candy, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - The House of Yes, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Pageant, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Old Pictures - 2003?, Circa 2003 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Calendar, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Communication, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Handbook/Procedures, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Spring Board Meetings, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Proposals, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - All School Party, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Marketing, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Press, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Programs/Posters, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Budget, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - All School Meetings, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Artistic Associates, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Season Planning, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Press, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Programs, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Various Cabaret Seasons, 1990s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Various Cabaret Posters, 1990s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Various Posters, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Tape, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Good Old Boys, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - 70 Scenes, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Woyzeck, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Coffin/Hole, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Cats Talk Back, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Hair, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Zanna Don't!, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Miss Julie, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Absolutely True, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Variety Show, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Le Jetee, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Landscape, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Chekhov, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Sincerity Forever, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Eiffel Tower Wedding Party, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Cannibal, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Bindlestiff Cirkus, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Assassins, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Assassins Script, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Press Clippings and Marketing, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Membership Forms, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Mr and Mrs Hollywood, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Might as Well Be Spring, or Bill Clinton Goes to the Bathroom, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Blood Box, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Bicycling for Ladies, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Perk/Pussy/Pathos, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Apocryphal Project, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Rise Up You Bloody Animals, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Finding Ways to Prove You're Not an Al-Qaeda Terrorist When You're Brown, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Hillbilly Antigone, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Help Wanted, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Chicano Sketches, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Amerigo in Wonderland, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Dancing in the Dark, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Estrella Cruz, the Junkyard Queen, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Sidewalk Opera, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Bone Songs, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Who Cares? We Do! Panel, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Down With Valentine's Day Party, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Homecoming Project, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Little Shop of Horrors, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Max Out Loud, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 131)